Hello from Athens, Greece, where it is
now 4:36 p.m. Uh, I am in an area of
Athens that I just love. It's called
Sidi. When I was living here between
1998 and 2000, CD was almost a no-go
area. It was largely abandoned,
abandoned warehouses, mostly light
industrial.
But then around 2000, artists began
moving in and opening small galleries or
small workshops. And then once the
artists came, the cafes and the
restaurants came and then the young
people came. And now it is the place to
be for nightife and restaurants and
clubs. And you are a stones throw from
the beautiful historic Parthonon which
you can see behind me. The Acropolis
which is the the hill that it sits on
right in the heart of everything.
Well folks as we speak the YouTube
channel is about to hit 250,000
subscribers. When we started I had high
hopes for this channel. I really did.
But I had no idea that we would hit this
number so quickly. It's ridiculous.
I cannot thank you enough for
commenting, for subscribing, for telling
your friends. We're improving every
week. I'm really proud of this show, but
we're improving thanks to the notes that
you guys leave. And I can't wait to keep
bringing you the show because we are
just getting started to tell you the
truth. And I don't want to I don't want
to spill the beans, but we have some big
plans for next year when we're going to
be, I think, big enough, hefty enough
that we can start bringing on some
A-list guests to uh to answer some tough
questions. And since we're in Athens,
I thought that we'd talk about a side of
this city that most tourists never hear
about, and that is terrorism,
assassinations, terrorist groups,
anarchism, spy wars, and a relationship
between American and Greek intelligence
that has at times been just an absolute
mess. I'll tell you some of those
stories later on in the show, but first
we have some genuinely 007 style
intrigue involving the current president
of the United States, Donald Trump.
Remember this strange story from a few
weeks ago? President Trump was leaving
the NATO summit in Turkey headed for the
UK when suddenly he announced that he
wasn't going to fly on his shiny new
guty gifted Air Force 747.
Well, instead Trump said that he was
switching back to the old Air Force One.
He said, "For old time's sake." Nobody
believed that, but we didn't have the
story
until now because this this was
happening in the middle of a war with
Iran. Everybody just assumed there was
some sort of a threat and just to be on
the safe side,
uh, the switch was made. There were
already reports that the president's new
cuttery jet didn't yet have all of the
defensive uh communications capabilities
of the old Air Force One. When reporters
raised those questions, the White House
just went ballistic. White House
communications director Steven Chung
attacked reporter uh Carol Lenig saying
this quote, "Carol Lenig is a liar and
this article is complete fake news. She
has no idea what she's talking about."
unquote.
That's not very nice. Well, it turns out
that the truth was considerably crazier
than what was being reported at the
time. And now we have video of the
transfer. According to new reporting
from the Washington Post, US officials
were worried about what they called a
credible Iranian threat against Trump or
against his aircraft. So, they didn't
just switch Trump's plane. They used an
airport catering truck to secretly
shuffle Trump onto a smaller plane after
he boarded Air Force One in view of the
television cameras. We're going to break
this down. Let's look at this this uh
video.
>> It sounds like a scene from a movie.
President Donald Trump was secretly
moved off of Air Force One in an airport
catering truck and transported to a
different plane without the world
knowing. The Washington Post broke the
story Monday night, reporting that the
ruse happened after the NATO summit in
Turkey. Photos released Tuesday from the
press pool traveling with the president
that day show three US government planes
on the tarmac in Ankura, Turkey. the new
Air Force One that Qatar gifted to the
president, a legacy Air Force One that
has flown presidents for decades, and a
smaller jet in the back that apparently
took center stage. The Post reports that
in Ankura, Trump boarded the old Air
Force One jumbo jet in view of
television cameras. He was secretly
shuttled minutes later to a smaller
plane, an Air Force C32A, via an airport
catering truck. The New York Times later
reported that after Mr. Trump arrived in
Britain, he was secretly moved back to
the older version of Air Force One. He
then disembarked in view of reporters
and walked across the tarmac to the
plane donated by Qatar, which he flew to
Washington. Security officials
reportedly thought the secret plane
change was necessary because of a
potential threat against the president
by Iran. The traveling press pool was
not told about the deception, meaning
they incorrectly thought the president
was on the old Air Force One with them.
In this particular case, it sure looks
like the press uh White House staffers,
the military members on board the plane
uh were potentially sitting ducks in a
case like this.
>> After the president boarded the Qatari
Air Force One in Britain later that
night, he was asked about concerns over
Iranian threats.
>> I'm number one on their list before you,
but if I go, you go.
>> It's not the first time a president was
covertly transported, though it's
unusual that the traveling press pool
was not clued in. In the year 2000,
President Clinton was traveling between
India and Pakistan and they actually put
him on a an unmarked plane uh to go
between those two countries. This
incident is putting renewed focus on
security concerns surrounding the new
Air Force One gifted by Qatar. Had that
plane been fully secured, this deception
might not have been necessary. The White
House did not respond to a request for
comment. Reporting at the White House,
Taylor's Spectrum News.
Yeah, boy. Oh boy, there's a lot to
unpack there. So, Trump eventually did
move back to Air Force One. It's not
clear how he moved from the C32A to the
old Air Force One after landing, but he
then got back aboard Air Force One to
take questions from journalists for 15
minutes, not acknowledging that that
change took place. Now, before we we go
on to another clip, I want to say that
one of the things that Trump did with
that kind of smart ale comment was he
confirmed
that the reporters that were on the
plane were sitting ducks. He got off the
plane and went on to the other plane to
save himself.
He didn't give a about the about
the reporters who were all on the plane
thinking that Trump was at the front of
it and just not taking questions. Uh
reporters in Washington are talking
about this a lot today and universally
they're angry. They're angry because the
president didn't show any concern for
their lives or their safety. Now another
another issue here is um was this really
legitimate intelligence? What we've
learned and we learned this from the
Turks. We're going to get to this in a
minute is that the intelligence came
from the Israelis. Well, of course it
came from the Israelis, but remember
other credible intelligence that the
Israelis gave us were immediately after
we started bombing Iran, they said that
there were Iranian terrorist cells in
every major city across the United
States.
Okay. So, where where are the arrests?
We have not seen one single arrest of a
an Iranian terrorist anywhere in the
United States.
Did they just make it up? I mean, you
might recall they're eating the dogs.
They're eating the cats. That was made
up. So were these terrorist cells all
across America. Never existed. So, did
the Israelis tell the White House that
there was a credible threat against the
president's life just to make Trump feel
indebted to them for saving him? I don't
know. I'm speculating.
This is the report from the Turks.
Turkey suspects Israel fabricated Trump
Air Force One assassination plot to
derail US Iran deal. Well, you know, one
of the interesting things is that
literally nobody is reporting
that the CIA had developed the same
information or that NSA had developed
the same information or MI6 or GCHQ or
the Australians or the French or the
Saudis or the Amiradis. Nobody else
was able to develop this information.
Only the Israelis.
So, we're supposed to believe that
either they got very, very lucky or they
are so good that they beat the pants off
of every other intelligence service in
the world and they single-handedly serve
to protect the president of the United
States. I'll let you decide.
Well, another issue that we have here is
the plane footage. I thought you would
get a kick out of seeing something like
this. JB, can you run this uh this clip?
So, here's the president going on the
new Air Force One, and he just
disappears inside it just like he
normally would. Now, what you see down
there is a catering truck. There's an
elevator on the other side of Air Force
One where the catering truck can drive
up to the elevator, load the food onto
it, it goes up into the actual body of
the plane, and everybody gets their
meals for the trip and their drinks and
coffee and what have you. But in this
case, the president was hiding inside
the catering truck
and then the catering truck took him to
the smaller jet in between the new Air
Force One and the old Air Force One,
loaded him onto the smaller jet. the
media gets on the the new Air Force One,
which is apparently the one that was
under threat from the Iranians and uh
and then everybody flew to the UK.
Well, once they get to the UK, Trump
gets off the smaller jet, secretly gets
back on Air Force One, flies to Andrews
Air Force Base, and everybody lives
happily ever after. And we're only
learning this now.
So, the bottom line is we're just going
to have to take the Israelis word for it
because we're never going to know if
there really was a uh a threat against
the president or not. What if the way
money works is about to change? Not
someday, not hypothetically, but right
now, China and the United States are
both making moves that suggest we could
be heading towards something the world
hasn't seen in more than 50 years, a
return to goldbacked money, or something
very close to it. China is shutting down
paper gold trading at four of its
biggest banks, all on the same day. And
they're building a new system that
settles on physical gold instead. On our
side, the government is sitting on more
than 8,000 tons of gold, still valued at
$42 an ounce on the books. Legislation
to fix that has already been introduced
in Congress. If both superpowers start
anchoring their currencies to gold, what
happens to the price? And more
importantly, what happens to every
dollar in your retirement that isn't
backed by anything at all? That's the
question that a free report from
American Alternative Assets answers.
It's called The Day Money Changes
Forever. And if you have an IRA or a
401k, you need to read it right now. Get
your free copy at johnlovesgold.com.
That's johnlovesgold.com
or call 1888gld053.
This whole incident got me wondering
about other historic escapes and there
were a couple that I knew about. In
1861, this is one of my favorite ones.
This was a legitimate plot. In 1861,
detectives uncovered the Pinkertons, by
the way. Pinkerton detectives uncovered
a plot to assassinate President-elect
Abraham Lincoln as his train was passing
through Baltimore. He was on his way to
Washington to take the oath of office.
This was March of 1861. So, get this. In
Baltimore,
he received 2% of the vote. Baltimore,
even though Maryland was a southern
state, but it did not it did not secede
from the Union. It did not join the
Confederacy. He just wanted to stay out
of it. But Maryland Marylanders hated
Abraham Lincoln. He got 2% of the vote
in Baltimore. Telegraph wires were cut
and the future president slipped through
Baltimore overnight wearing a softfelt
hat and a shawl.
Detective Kate Warner
repeat reportedly posed as as Lincoln's
sister while Lincoln hid behind in a
sleeping car.
He made it safely to Washington. He took
the oath of office and then got roasted
by the press for sneaking into town.
Universally,
the media in 1861 called Abraham Lincoln
a coward because he wouldn't, you know,
face his assassins like a man. Can you
imagine?
200 years before that, King Charles II
in 1651 famously climbed and hid inside
an oak tree after losing the Battle of
Worcester. He successfully hid there for
a day and then he went on the run for
six weeks so as not to be caught and
probably executed.
Fidel Castro survived decades of
assassination attempts. Some that sound
like like rejected Austin Power scenes.
Seriously. Poison pills, exploding
seashells, exploding cigars, a
contaminated skin diving suit.
Ridiculous. And then there's the closest
historical comparison to what Trump just
did. And amazingly, we only learned
about this yesterday. Bill Clinton
pulled a similar pain uh plane switch
maneuver in 2000 during a secret trip to
Pakistan. But there was one big
difference. The White House told
journalists what was happening while it
was happening. White House reporter for
USA Today, Susan Page, revealed that she
was briefed by White House security
officials about the threat on the
president, which put her own life in
danger. as far as why she revealed the
story now, she said, quote, "I haven't
spoken about this episode before, but
because of the off thereord ground rules
of that discussion, and since more than
a quarter century has passed, and since
the roose became evident as soon as
President Clinton disembarked in
Pakistan, I think it's okay for me to
relay it now."
Well, this brings us to the part of
Trump's operation that has the White
House press corps furious. I mentioned
it a moment ago because while Trump was
secretly being driven across the airport
in a catering truck, the journalists
traveling with him were left just
sitting on the decoy plane. They weren't
told that Trump had escaped in the
catering truck. They weren't told that
there was another aircraft taking off.
They weren't even told, "Hey, listen.
Uh, we're having some engine trouble or
comm's trouble. you might want to just
take a United Airlines flight back or
whatever. The White House could have
done that. They weren't even told that
they might be participating in a
presidential security operation. The
only clue that something unusual was
happening. The Secret Service suddenly
ordered everybody on the plane to close
their window shades.
You can see in this photo, the window
shades were closed on Air Force One.
reporters had no idea why. The White
House pool reporter just said it was an
order. They were ordered to close the
shades. He said, quote, "At one point, a
photographer seated behind me opened his
shade and was quickly instructed to
close it again." We asked a wrangler
why, and they only said it was a request
from the Secret Service." unquote. Well,
listen to what the president said after
he snuck back on board Air Force One and
then spoke with reporters
>> of any credible threat by Iran against
Air Force One.
>> I have a threat all the time. I'm number
one on their list before you. But if I
go, you go.
>> Right.
>> But was there perhaps perhaps someday
you want to change professions?
I'll tell you that is that is
cold-hearted,
mean-spirited. And as I said, it's the
talk of Washington today among the press
corps. And there's one additional
wrinkle to this story. You might be
wondering about the details of this
alleged plot to kill the president. This
is something I I mentioned a few minutes
ago and how credible or incredible
the information was. The aircraft switch
happened in Turkey during the NATO
summit after intelligence on the
assassination attempt came from Israel
and Turkish officials suspect the
Israeli intelligence report was just a
ruse to undermine negotiations with
Tehran as reported in the Middle East
eye. The story says, quote, "During his
meeting with President, Turkish
President Reep Erdogan, Trump repeatedly
said that the war with Iran had ended
and expressed hope about the
negotiations." A source who attended the
meeting told Middle East eye. Turkish
officials now say they believe the
Israeli intelligence report was probably
a roose by Netanyahu's government to
portray itself as protecting Trump,
derail negotiations with Iran, and
undermine Trump's apparently close
relationship with Erdogan," unquote.
I think that's probably true. You know,
if I were to rate this escape on a scale
of 1 to 10, it's got to be a 10. It
worked. Nobody had any idea. It only
came out later when somebody finally
started talking.
I do not believe that there was a
credible threat on the president's life.
The Israelis do things like this to us
all the time. It's it's a manipulation
tactic.
And let me tell you a little bit about
this guttery 747.
I've mentioned in past
podcasts that I have friends in five of
the six Persian Gulf royal families and
I stay in close touch with with most of
them. When the cuties decided to gift
this 747, it came in reaction to
President Trump asking them, "Will you
give me a free Boeing 747?"
They were offended. according to this
royal family member. But Arab culture is
such that you can't deny a request for
hospitality. Right now, most people ask
for a glass of water or a cup of tea,
not a 747. But the the gutteries
couldn't say no to the request. But they
were so offended that the president
would come right out and ask for a free
747 that when they finally turned it
over to the US government, they made an
announcement that it was a gift from the
people of Qatar to the people of the
United States, that it was not a gift to
Donald Trump. Well, the president
oneuped them a couple of weeks ago by
announcing that when he completes his
term, he's taking the 747 and parking it
at what will be the Donald Trump
Presidential Library and it'll be on
display there. So, he will be the only
president to uh to ride in it. And let
me tell you my own story.
In November 1999, Bill Clinton
came here to Athens. When
a president comes to a country that you
are assigned to, it doesn't matter if
you are CIA or State Department or
Commerce Department or agriculture
department. They don't care who you work
for. Everybody has to pitch in and help.
Ambassador Nicholas Burns,
whom I have always disliked and
disrespected, on this one occasion did
the right thing. He put all the jobs
that needed to be done into a hat. And
we all took turns picking our job out of
a hat. I hit the lottery. And the job
that I picked out of the hat was to be
the notetaker in President Clinton's
meeting with the Greek prime minister,
defense minister, and foreign minister.
I've told that story many times, but
here's a side to that story I've never
told.
When the meeting was done, President
Clinton went to the basement from the
top floor to the basement of the
Intercontinental Hotel about two miles
that way and he gave a rockous speech,
wildly popular speech to the Greek
American Business Women's Association.
From that speech, he then went to Athens
airport, the old airport at Elinikon,
and
flew back to Washington.
I went back to the embassy and we had
something called a hot wash, which is an
afteraction report.
And that's when everybody gets together
and you talk about absolutely every
detail of the visit. What went right,
what went wrong, what lessons learned.
And the ambassador says to everybody
when he calls us all together, "Do you
want to hear something crazy?" He said,
"Just as the plane is taking off, the
telephone inside Air Force One rang
and it was a random
bomb threat. Someone here in Greece
got the top secret phone number for the
Air Force One telephone.
Not to say Bill Clinton answered the
phone. He didn't answer the phone. Some
low-level aid answered the phone. But it
was a bomb threat to blow up Air Force
One. So, did the Israelis lie? Probably.
But you have to take every shred of
information like this seriously just in
case it's legit. Wait, you're still
guessing you're zero? Because if you
are, you're wasting ammo and missing
shots you should be making. Every time
you adjust your optic the old school
way, you're burning time, burning cash,
and hoping you got it right. And when it
counts, hope is not a strategy. That's
why MCG Tactical dropped the bore, a
precision caliber zeroing tool that lets
you dial in your shot in seconds, not
hours. We're talking one-handed setup,
laser accurate alignment, and repeatable
precision that locks your zero fast. No
guesswork, no wasted rounds, just clean,
confident shots every time you pull the
trigger. And right now, they're running
a ridiculous offer. over 80% off. Plus,
they're throwing in a free tanto knife.
But here's the catch. Inventory is
tight. When these are gone, they're
gone. So, if you're serious about your
accuracy, stop guessing. Go to
mcgac.com/johore
jhn
b o a r right now. Lock yours in before
they sell out. I want to talk a little
bit more about grease tube. For those of
you who watch the show regularly or who
know me personally,
I love Greece almost more than any other
place on Earth. I've been coming here
since I was
20 years old, right?
19 or 20, whatever. And I just love the
place. I I hope that someday I can buy a
little apartment right here in this
neighborhood and uh and spend a few
months a year maybe writing books on a
balcony overlooking the the beautiful
Parthonon.
I served here with the CIA from 1998 to
2000.
It was the most dangerous tour I ever
had in my career. And I served in
Pakistan. I served in Afghanistan. I
served in Iraq. And I never feared for
my safety like I feared for it right
here in Greece. When I was serving in
Greece, the US government spent more
money on security than it spent anywhere
else on the planet, including Beirut,
which was exploding at the time. And
that is because of two groups. Neither
group exists any longer.
One, the more lethal of the two was
called Revolutionary Organization 17
November, the Gano Envir. The other one
was called Popular Revolutionary
Struggle. 17 November carried out 27
assassinations between December 23rd,
1975 and April of 2000.
The last assa assassination was of my
next door neighbor, Brigadier General
Steven Saunders. He was the British
defense attaches. I've told this story
many times, but uh a couple of months
after Steven was assassinated, 17
November mailed a manifesto to a
left-wing newspaper. This is something
they usually did. They would either drop
a manifesto at the site of the hit or
leave it in a garbage can, call a
leftist newspaper and tell them where to
find it, or mail it to the newspaper.
And usually they did it within a day or
two of the hit.
In the case of Steven's assassination,
they waited months. They waited until
August of uh of 2000.
And they said in this manifesto,
Megaloascopos, we saw the big spy,
but he was driving an armored car and we
knew he was armed.
So, we elected to carry out the
revolutionary sentence on the war
criminal Saunders. Now, Steve was not a
war criminal. He had served in the
British Army in Northern Ireland and in
Yugoslavia, but he was a paper pusher.
He was not a war criminal.
Um, but they had intended to kill me
that day and he was a softer target.
He lived about 20 minutes after they
shot him. They blew his right hand
completely off at the wrist. They shot
him in the chest with the same
45 that they used to carry out most of
their assassinations.
It was called the Welch 45 because it
was used to kill CIA station chief
Richard Welch on December 23rd, 1975.
They also killed uh two US defense
ataches and and a hapless
low-level African-American Air Force
tech sergeant who was doing his laundry
in the in the basement laundry room of
his apartment building.
They um self-destructed in uh early
2000. One of the 17 November bombers was
carrying a bomb in a brown paper bag in
Pereus, the port city of Athens.
He was going to use it to blow up the
car of a wealthy Greek ship owner.
Instead, the bomb went off in his hands,
blew his hands completely off, blew his
right eye out, and he was bleeding to
death. A policeman across the street
heard the explosion. He ran over, tried
to stench the the flow of the blood and
the bomber confessed that he was 17
November's bomber and that his two
brothers were among the assassins. And
he named all the members of the
organization and he gave the policeman
the address of the safe house where all
the weapons and the explosives were
killed and then he lived. The cop
actually saved his life.
So the Greek counterterrorism police
used that information to break the group
within a day. The primary assassin, the
Mitis Ku Fontinas, who was known as the
Black Hand because everything he touched
died,
uh, briefly escaped. He was found, of
all places, on a nudist beach on one of
the Greek islands and finally captured
there.
Most of the members of 17 November have
been released from prison. The primary
assassins, five of them are still in
prison. The founder of the group was
released from prison on parole a month
ago for good behavior. And there was
such an uproar and an outcry
that the Supreme Court reversed his
release and he went back to prison.
Greece is no longer dangerous like that.
In fact, there's very little crime here
of any kind. And I hate to even say
this, but much of the crime comes from
undocumented migrants and refugees who
are, you know, stealing to eat to
survive.
That's a whole different issue we can
talk about at some future time.
There are still
terrorist incidents, but they're not
necessarily not necessarily carried out
by terrorist groups so much as anarchist
groups that just literally want to throw
a grenade into the middle of the room
and see what happens.
Those of us who lived in Greece in
the '9s or in 2000 used to say that that
Athens was a wannabe ro Rome. that
Athens was Rome 20 or 30 years earlier.
Dirty, rundown, not advanced.
Now Rome wishes it was Athens. That's
how great it is. Greece doesn't have
those kinds of problems anymore. And
that is a very very good thing. Um I'll
I'll add one more
little detail to my story and I say this
in my first book. One of the things that
I'll never forgive myself for,
I was shocked when I saw that manifesto
that day. Shocked because not only was I
particularly good at surveillance and
surveillance detection, I actually
became a surveillance and surveillance
detection instructor at the CIA. And I
wrote a book called The CIA Insiders
Guide to Surveillance and Surveillance
Detection. And for years,
for years, I've talked about how in the
world they found me, and I never noticed
them.
The conclusion we came to was that
Steven was a media He He never
saw a camera that he didn't want to jump
right in front of and give a big toothy,
you know, interview.
And then they noticed my license plate
and noticed that it was an American
embassy license plate. And when they
looked at my car, they saw it was
armored. and they made the correct
assumption that I was a CIA officer.
That's the conclusion. Well,
a month after Steven's assassination, my
mom and dad came to visit me here in
Greece. I was married at the time, and I
had two little boys. They were, let me
think, they were seven and four at the
time. They're grown men now, of course.
And um
I was standing in front of the house one
day with my mom and the boys and I said,
"Mom, let me take a picture of you and
the boys." And my mom crouched down and
put her arms around the boys and all
three of them are smiling.
Months passed. Now, this was the days
when you had to get film developed,
right? You had to take it to Kodakchrome
or whatever the little the little hut
that was in the parking lot of the the
grocery store.
It was months before I got those
pictures developed. And in the picture
of my mom hugging the boys, there's a
man sitting in a red Toyota
and he's just staring at the camera.
He's looking right at the camera. And I
never noticed him. And guess who he
turned out to be?
Stephen Saunders assassin. I got very
lucky that day.
I still I still think about Stephen.
Well, folks, yesterday was actually a
really important
uh day for American elections, primary
elections, big big DSA races, Democratic
Socialists of America. DSA and pro
Palestine candidate Peggy Flanigan
pulled off a major win in the Minnesota
US Senate race. This is the Democratic
primary. In Wisconsin's governor's race,
there was a huge loss for the DSA
candidate, State Representative
Franchesca Hong. The main story in that
race is that the polling was absolutely
terrible. Listen, over the last 10
years, polling has been notoriously bad
anyway. And it's because it's almost
impossible to poll people now
accurately
because nobody has landlines anymore.
you know, you can't say, "Well, I need
40%, you know, white middle class people
and they live in these areas." Everybody
uses cell phones or or the internet. So,
each poll ahead of election day had
Franchesca Hong up by at least 20
points. We have a really cool graphic
here. Look at this. State Navigate, she
was up by 22. Public policy polling and
PPP is good. Up by 18. Marquette
University also good up by 25. State
Navigate up by 29. Here's another PPP
from a couple of days earlier up by 20.
And the results she lost by half of 1%.
Now, I will add too that Wisconsin is
the most purple of the purple states. It
can go Democratic, it can go Republican,
it can go down to the wire. And we don't
know who won the state for days in a
presidential race. They've got a
Democratic senator. They've got a
Republican senator. They have a
Democratic governor right now. The last
governor was Republican. The the
congressional delegation is divided
between Democrats and Republicans. You
just never know. It's all about turnout.
And when the polling is bad just by its
nature, it's just impossible to poll in
a purple state. Well, all of this comes
after Abdul Sed in Michigan pulled off
that narrow win in the Democratic uh
Senate race.
So, so far
DSA aligned candidates,
especially those who have been endorsed
by Bernie Sanders, are pulling off major
upsets mostly.
The thing is, and this is what is the
most interesting to me,
are we seeing the Democrats version of
the Tea Party? We might be. I don't know
how many of you remember the election of
2010.
I remember the election 2010 because I
was working on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee at the time and the
conventional wisdom we all believed was
that the Republicans were going to win a
ton of Senate seats. The Democrats were
going to lose their majority and John
was going to lose his job. Right?
But the Tea Party,
which has become the MAGA movement by
and large, the Tea Party
picked off a whole bunch of moderate
Republican senators. And so in states
where these moderate Republican senators
were popular incumbents,
the Democrats won. The Democrats won in
Missouri that year. The Democrats won in
Indiana that year. The Democrats won in
Montana and the Democrats won a race in
in Delaware, Joe Biden's old Senate seat
that they were predicted to lose.
And so I'm wondering if we're seeing the
same thing now among Democrats where DSA
aligned candidates pretty hard left by
DNC standards are picking off incumbents
only to then lose to moderate
Republicans in the general election.
We've got a clip uh of Francesca Hong
that I think is really funny. JB, do you
mind running that clip? I know we've
already talked about her, but it's kind
of funny to me.
>> Cooked many great Thanksgiving dinners
and I'm not going to cancel
Thanksgiving.
>> How do you make the pivot to November,
especially as voters are learning about
you through those attack ads about
Thanksgiving comments about uh the
proximity to whiteness comment? How do
you make the pivot to November to voters
uh who may not know much about you
outside of that? delivering on
solutions, fully funding public schools,
taxing the ultra rich, moratorium on
data centers, universal child care, pay
for all legislation that I've introduced
and champion and will continue to fight
for as governor.
>> Okay,
I'm for just about all those things.
But what she was referring to in the
beginning was she made statements in the
past saying that she wanted to either
cancel Thanksgiving or change the name
of Thanksgiving.
Almost nobody in America wants to do
that.
And so attack ads came out uh in in this
race against her saying she is so off
the charts when it comes to personal
ideology that she wants to cancel
Thanksgiving. That's why she started off
by saying, "I have lots of great
Thanksgivings. I'm not going to cancel
Thanksgiving." Well, then why'd you say
you're going to cancel Thanksgiving
if you're not. What a stupid thing to
say. Another thing, and one of our
producers, JB and I were talking about
this before we started filming, was
I'm sure many of you have seen this what
I consider to be an absolutely hilarious
video on YouTube of the it's like the
2020 or 2022 DSA convention in Los
Angeles. If you if you go into YouTube
and type that in, it'll pop up.
they couldn't get any work done because
somebody's saying you use the wrong
pronouns
or um people please stop the cross talk.
I have an auditory problem and I'm
beginning to freak out.
Come on, that's not America.
Most Americans don't want candidates
that are going to scream at us about
pronouns. I will not call anybody Z or
Zur. Sorry, not going to happen. And I
consider myself to be progressive. But
anyway, this may be just a little bit
too much for many Americans. And I'm
wondering if that's what we saw in this
Wisconsin race. There was another
significant upset
on uh on Tuesday. And this is in
Connecticut's first congressional
district. Representative John Larson has
been in Congress for 28
years and he lost to an upstart named
Luke Bronin. Now, you may you may
remember Congressman Larson from quite
an unfortunate thing that happened. And
you see here on this chart, he got
clobbered 54.4
to 32.8. You've been in Congress for 28
years and you get less than 33%.
There's something terribly wrong. But
what I want to show you too here is
look, there were fewer than 48,000 votes
cast. Fewer than 48,000 votes cast. You
know how many people are in that
congressional district? 1.2 million
people.
Yeah. And 38,000 bothered to go to the
polls and vote.
So, Democrats should be warned.
And I say this every two years because
this seems to be the Democrats election
theory.
Vote for me because I'm not the other
guy.
Well, you have to stand for something.
And if you don't stand for anything,
people aren't going to go to the polls
to vote for you. I think that's what we
saw in this case. I wanted to show you
this this clip, too, of Congressman
Larson. It might ring a ring a bell.
Don't worry, no one on the Republican
side in the House and Senate who control
both the House and Senate is going to
speak up
and challenge us.
But we need to pro protect Americans
privacy
and their social security.
For 40%
of all Americans,
Social Security
is the
basis for their
retirement
and their retirement
savings.
And uh
>> let's stop it there. JB,
the conventional wisdom at the time, of
course, was that he was having a stroke.
His office said at the time that
no, he was a little dehydrated.
He hadn't slept very well the night
before.
But the thing is, when you're in your
70s or 80s or in some cases 90s, maybe
it's time to step aside and let the
younger generation come in and do their
thing.
Well, the voters of Connecticut's first
district made that decision for him
yesterday. There was also news on the
Republican side. I don't know why I'm so
interested in the South Carolina Senate
race.
My feelings about Lindsey Graham are
well known. his sister Darlene
um was coronated
in this uh in this situation only
because she happened to be Lindsey
Graham's sister.
So now she's Senator Darlene Graham and
there are other Republicans, qualified
Republicans in South Carolina saying not
so fast, she's not qualified to be a
United States senator. Well, the race
was Tuesday
and
she came in first. That's not saying
much. There were a whole bunch of people
running and she only ended up with
32.7%.
So now she's going to run against Ralph
Norman in a runoff. The runoff will
come, I don't remember the date, but
it's coming soon. It's going to be like
six weeks from now. Uh
I don't think she's a shoein. I don't
think people
respect her. And I think that most South
Carolinians
don't have any idea who the heck she is
other than Lindsey Graham's sister.
And I'll tell you what, Lindsey Graham
just died what, like the other day, and
the Defense Department already named a
military base after him called Joint
Base Lindsey Graham.
Nice, huh?
So, listen. In politics so far, 10 10 US
House members have lost their primaries.
10. That is the most since 1970.
You remember that mantra from the the
famous film Network?
I'm mad as hell and I'm not going to
take this anymore.
That's what the American voters are
saying.
So, until next time. Actually, you know
what? I'll tell you. Our next episode I
am going to film from Cairo, Egypt. And
I hope I have a good view to show you
from there. Thanks for joining us.
Please find my other podcast. It's
called John Kuryaku's Deadrop. It's on
Apple Podcasts and Spotify. Uh we're
also on X, on Facebook, on LinkedIn, on
Instagram, and pretty much everywhere
else. Thanks again for helping us by
liking, subscribing, commenting, making
recommendations. It really means a lot
to me.